<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-bicycle-fashion</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1887-07-16/ed-1/?sp=2&q=bicycle+BICYCLES+WOMEN</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        BICYCLES FOB WOMEN.
        A novelty promised tor this rail Is a bicycle for
        lady riders. There are several ralr riders In this
        city ready to take to this lady bicycle when It
        comes. It will be so arranged that a ladv who
        will learn to ride It can do so with as much
        grace and propriety as she could ride a tricycle.
        It will be a modification or tue Hover type or
        bicycle for gentlemen with the backbone or irame
        curved downward like the letter U between the
        wheels, so that when the lady sits upon the sad
        dle there will be no obstruction in the way or her
        dress between her feet and the saddie. i he only
        trouble," said the dealer, "win be in mounting.
        Ladle.-&gt who ride will have to have gentlemen wltn
        them to assist them In mounting." Wuen the
        veioclpede came out early In the century, ma
        chines with the C shaped bacKbone were con
        structed lor and used by the great grandmothers
        or the present race oi tncyclera.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1895-06-02/ed-1/?sp=7&q=BICYCLE+Bicycle+bicycle+bicycles+bicycling+Bicycling+costume+Costume+costumer+costumes+Costumes+COSTUMES+tailor&r=-0.026,0.134,0.795,0.427,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        SOME OF THE LOCAL WOMEN CYCLERS
        While tho superiority and irresistible
        fascination of cycling is a point yielded
        by all, there is still considerable agita
        tion and discussion in the matter of pro
        priety in costume. That, of course, is and
        will probably remain a matter of taste.
        Most, of tho dealers contend that a dia
        mond frame wheel is us advantageous for
        women as for men, and if that be proven
        by test and experience, some modifica
        tion or extenuation of tho obnoxious and
        derision-ha.inted bloomers will probably
        bo discovered or invented, as evory other
        demand iv nature and art has heretofore
        been supplied sooner or later.
        At present a natty skirt, rather shorter
        than walking length, with corduroy or
        leather leggings to the knee, and a trim
        snort I jacket or bodice, seems to answer
        every purnose for the present make of
        lady s wheel. Such a costume is practica
        ble, in no way conspicuous, and appears
        to bo the generally accepted model for a
        cycling costume. Perhaps artor a little
        the women who don't wear bloomers now
        because they "don't wish to be conspic
        uous," will not be found without the 01—
        for tho same reason. Quien sahc? Stranger
        things have happened.

        The one disadvantage of wearing
        bloomers is that when you fall off a bi
        cycle nobody knows whether you have
        frilled underwear on or nut. This is
        discouraging to some girls.
        Tncre is no oi-chloride of gold cure for
        the bloomer habit. When a woman once
        gets a taste tor hloomeis you might as
        well satisfy her craving tirst as last.
        ISiooineis are all rigtit and let them
        come, whether of the fullblown variety
        or of the kind that arc nipped in the bud
        —just abovo tho knee.

        The modern woman is knock kneed-
        She will probably loudly deny'the charge.
        Nay, more, she may be utterly ignorant
        of her defect. She may believe that her
        legs arc like unto Diana's when tho god
        dess leads her nymphs. But the truth
        remains, the average modern woman is
        knock-kneed. I lor physicians will tell
        her so. if other authorities aro not surti
        cient to convince her, sava the New York
        World.
        Had she been. wise, the fact might
        never have been known. Attired in volu
        minous draperiees. with skirts distended
        many yards abv&gtut her, no one could
        dream that hei legs wero other than the
        straightest, shapeliest ones possiolc. But
        she donned knickerbockers. She took to
        divided skirts and clothed herself in
        In New York
        Turkish trousers. Sne mounted a bicycle
        and th? truth was known. The average
        woman's logs show a tendency to con
        vert to a point at the knees, und hei bi
        cycle suit has shown it. The reason for
        this sao affliction is not pi tin. Perhur s
        it airaes from the fact that tb*s average
        Woman has heen. until recently, more oc
        cupied in anointing her face with com
        plexion lotions than in developing iter
        body. She has preferred riding in the
        elevated train to walking, and has chosen
        staying in the housi rather tlutn tramp
        ing, iter knees huvu in the meantime
        been preparing a quiet little revenge for
        their enforcod inactivity.
        Another explanation of tho knock-kneed
        tendency of women is advanced by some
        unregenerate and irreligious being who
        Los A nifties Poems
        says that women have knelt too ofton
        and too long. They have gone to chinch
        often and have knelt for long periods:
        they have knelt by cradles, adoring little,
        unintelligent, red-faced morsels of hu
        manity: and the man who advances this
        explanation of the knock-kneed woman
        maintains that it is her devotion to one
        or another object which has caused this
        grave defect.
        Whatever may be the cause, the fact
        remains. Look at the next group of
        trousered feminine bycichsts you happen
        to see. and observe if there i.s not that
        curve above the leather gaiters and below
        the Hannel trousers which reveals the im
        perfection.
        The cure is, of course, in exercising the
        knee until it assumes its proper propo?
        tfons and its proper relation to the leg.
        Walking, bicycle riding.swimming or any
        other exercise which develops the legs,
        will help to correct tho detect.. Until
        such time as it is corrected the woman
        who loves grace will wear garments dis
        playing less freely her imperfections.

        Bicycle leggings, gaiters, boots and
        shoes ol special design are shown in tbe
        shoe stores and department stores in
        great variety, says a writer in the Now
        York World. The fashionable makers
        of custom shoes tind an incidental boom
        in cheir business directly connected with
        the bicycle craze aud some of their fin ?st
        and costliest work is in the lino of laced
        or buttoned leggings and boots of extra
        length in tbe legs.
        A Sixth avenue dealer in boots and
        shoes has issued an illustrated.catalogue
        devoted entirely to ladies' and gentle
        men's bicyclo footwear. Designers ia
        shoe factories are racking their brains
        for new ideas in leggings and boots.
        The latter come in all shades of russet
        and tan. They are made with an extra
        long top. reaching to the center of tho
        call. They come in laces and differ only
        from the ladies' hunting boot, or boot
        for mountain wear, In that for bicycle
        use tlio sole must be single, thin and
        flexible.
        Comfortable as such a boot is. it is in no
        such favor among tho fair cyclers as
        leggings worn witli approved bicycle
        shoes. The latter conic in two styles,
        Oxford tios and plain frontla. c teaching
        just above the ankle. The soles are
        thin and the heel is low and flat. The
        Oxford ties are made up iv do'igola.
        patent leather, tans, russet calf and can
        vas. The regulation bicycle shoe, laced
        to support the ankle, is made in dongola,
        calf and canvas. Rubber or leather soles
        are optional, but rubber is no longer con
        sidered the pioper tiling. Tbe rat-trap
        pedals make tbe rubber soles unnecessary.
        Tbe legging is a necessity with either
        style of these shoes and it is in their
        construction that tlie designers of foot
        wear navo given to tbe tiado their best
        efforts.
        One window shows over sixty stylos of
        leggings. They are made up to button
        and to lace ami to lace with button effect,
        ami comprize ooze calf in the undressed
        or suede style and in all the rich tan
        tints, russet, wdiitc, red and brown Rus
        sia calf; enamelled calf in black, red and
        russet; dongola kid, kangaroo kid, cor
        duroy in gray, black, blue and purple;
        canvas in a variety of shades und heavy
        cloth specially woven for this purpose in
        every color likely to be worn in the con
        struction of bicycling costumes, itlues
        and grays predominate, and it is possi
        ble to match any of the prevailing shades
        of outing cloth in any of tbe big retail
        stores.
        Tan leggings are, however, supposed
        to go well with Buy costume. Leggings
        icady-inado range in value fioni X to $7.
        A w oman of the Mlcbaux club who in
        deference tuber high social position must
        have everything ruauo to order, pays
        from 113 CO $i"&gt for her leggings.
        Tho laced pattern worn by the ladies of
        the Lyceum company during the long rim
        of The Amazons is much affected, they
        are made Ol either ooze calf or russet leath
        er of russet color, velvety and rich in ap- 1
        pearanoe, and must fit like v glove fiom
        ankle to knoe. To do this and not ii ter
        ferc with tlie free motion of tbe limb is a
        triumph of tbe cordwainer's art. Tho
        greatest care must be taken in tbe cutting
        out ol leggings of this class. A slight
        mistako in measurement or cutting will
        ruin them in the eyes of tho fastidious
        costumer. That is why he charges $26,
        IMen are not overgiven to wearing leg
        gings as part of a bicyclo costume, pre
        ferring to show their manly limbs through
        the medium of plaid stockings. The
        bicycle legging for men is a simple affair
        closely resembling tbe riding legging in
        appearance. The bicycle legging, how
        ever, is not held to tbe blub by a strap
        under tbe foot, but rests lightly or. tho
        top of,the foot. They ire really intended
        as a protection in long journeys, and in
        the stores are shown only in corduroys,
        canvas and leather. Tlio low-quarter
        dongola kid or canvas shoe of Oxford tio
        pattern, with an especially stout flat heel
        and with a leather side, is the correct
        thing in men's bicyclo shoes.

        Antwerp's cvhibition was a financial
        success afHr all: the shareholders have
        been repaid the amount they Invested,
        with 1!&gt per cent additional.
        WHAT ONE MAY WEAR
        Comfort One Thing to Be
        Considered Then Comes
        Style
        SOME VERY UNIQUE COSTUMES
        Somber Blacks and Modest Blues Are
        Overshadowed by the Gay
        Costumes Seen
        Interest in conventional dress is rapidly
        disappearing and forms a less interesting
        topic of conversation among the fair sex
        than ever before. Now we bear on all
        sides, "what, kind of a bicycle costume
        have you; is your skirt narrow or wide,
        and your leggins a good tit about the
        ankles?"
        Die latest thing in the way ot skirts
        has just been Introduced. It Has a di
        vided skill ofrei'i, in the back, while from
        tho front it seems t) be an" ordinary
        tailor-made cycling suit. The woman
        who wears one of these will have to take
        lessons in dressing from her father, hus
        band or brother, and alas! for her who
        has nono of these! for the new skirt is
        got into just as a man gets into.hi., trous
        ers. Ttie underskirt made of the same
        material as the suit! is buttoned up In
        front, and tbe outer skirt is fastened over
        this by means of a row of buttons on
        each aide. The back has side plaits,
        meeting In tne middle at the waist, and
        the middle seam is fastened all the way
        dawn to the bottom of the skirt, which
        makes the adjustment in mounting ex
        ceedingly simple. The skirt, instead of
        hanging one-fifth on tho right, and fou
        fifths on the left side of the wheel, fa!ls
        e\cnlv divided, and is remarkably grace
        ful and modest, both when tbe wearer is
        walking and when she is riding. Around
        blazer coat, with flaring fronts, is worn
        with this skirt, aud leggins and caps come
        In the same material the matetial is an
        imported pepper-and-salt mixture, and is
        calculated to stand wear and tear, and
        dust.
        In saleo!!ng a costume there is one
        tiling that every woman, stout or lean,
        ricli or poor, should insist upon, and
        that is that the ikilt shall be opened on
        tlie sides and not in the back. Nothing
        looks worse on a wheel than a placKot
        gaping and awry.
        Something entirely new in tho way ol
        a cap has a soft crown, turned up with
        wings, and a stiff visor in front. This
        comes only in black, and is particularly
        adapted to older women.
        Por t'.iose whose faces are dainty and
        piquant the white duck Tarns are very
        becoming, and added to this, they laun
        dry easily.
        Tho tendency of women riders to wear
        dark suits entirely, may hi somewhat
        doubted when one learns that the latest
        in a cycling costume seen on a young
        rider,was guile a gaudy affair. The skirt
        was green tweed with white shirt and
        leather belt, cuffs and collars. Her red
        serge blazer coat shone out daringly with
        its twinkling gold buttons. To tv is she
        bad added red serge knickerbockers and
        a soft red felt hat. She had red ribbons
        tied to her wheel, and she looked as if
        lifo was good and May tbe best of all
        months of the year.
        I.wss showy, but quite as novel, may be.
        was a green cloth cycling suit,with white
        silk blouse, all frills and rlutliness. Over
        this came a green Figaro jacket, faced
        with white and a belt and necktie of tar
        tan red and green. No skirt at all was
        visible, but the knickerbockers wero so
        full you wouldn't have known the differ
        ence until you got to the Knees. At the
        knees they stopped and tartan stockings
        took their place helped out by soft cy
        cling shoes.
        The new stylo of the jersey for cycling
        is the prettiest thing imaginable. It lits
        tl o form closely, buttoning from each
        shoulder to the neck and having immense
        leg-o'-mutton sleeves which give ita truly
        feminine look. It is purchasable In plain
        colors or in Stripes. Durng the long warm
        rides tbe collar may be turned In, leaving
        tbe neck free and comfortable.
        The girl who seeks comfort even at the
        expense ol her figure will don the new
        corset waist. Any dressmaker may fash
        ion ibis garment from strong, elastic,
        washablo material. The only stiffening
        used is the wlmlebones along the center
        of tlie uack. The buttons fasten with
        loops of rubber.
        Many women wonder what to do with
        their skirts to keep them in place. If of
        cloth, a shot put into the insido of the
        hem will keep them nicely from Hying.
        If of washable material, live little open
        ings in the hem. wherein may be tacked
        live small, lead dress WjigbtS, should bo
        left when the skirt is being made.

        Bicycling is becoming so genoral that
        I any new device for adding to the comfort
        I f riders is of more than passing interest.
        Here are two. for example, that we illus
        trate for the benefit of the cyclists among
        our readers, says the Daily Report.
        First is a trouser guard, .rbich, in some
        form, is almost Indispensable when tbe
        rider is in ordinary street dress. The
        guard here shown has tho advantage of
        tiot binding the trousers around the
        ankle and thus creasing them out of
        shape; on tbe contrary, it keeps them in
        shape. It is made of steel wire, flattened
        at tbe'tnoutb of the guard, and slips on
        and off vory easily.
        Tho other illustration shows a skirt
        holder for women. By its use the skirt
        To Keep the Skirts Trim
        is prevented from flying up, thus secur
        ing safety and neatness at the same time.
        What a Woman Did
        Miss Julia Spillane of Denver demon
        strates uailv what a woman with pluck
        and a wheel can do. She is traveling
        through Colorado, Wyoming, Nebraska
        and lowa in the interest of Cycling West,
        soliciting subsciiptions. She has been
        on tlie road for several montns. and has
        met with unparalleled succeßS. The
        wheelmen all along the line have ex
        tended to her every courtesy. .Miss Smb.
        lane is a rationalist. and*on« (if the lirst
        women ir, the west to appear in knicker
        bockers. She says: "Weather perniit-
        Por the Cycler
        ting, I rode my wheel in nearly every
        city and town visisted."
        Her latest long ride was from Kearney,
        Nebrasksa, to (fraud Island, a distance
        Of fdtty-tive miles, and from tnere to
        Fremont, where she met with snow and
        ice, tramping it from tneie to Omaha.
        Among the many noted women who
        ride bicycles in England, few, if any,
        possess a prettier wheel than Lady Dudley.
        Her machine is enamelled white and
        lined with blue and gold, lilted with real
        ivory handles. Lady Dudley is in the
        habit of taking long rides unaccom
        panied.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1895-06-23/ed-1/?sp=14&q=bicycle+Bicycle+Bicycles+bicycles+bicycling+Bicycling+fashion+women&r=-0.116,0.679,0.662,0.414,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Don't wear a black sweater in the sum
        tacr.
        Don't, oh don't appear in public on a
        Wheel wearing a silk hat.
        Don't wear "toeclips" just because
        Zimmerman and Johnson use them.
        Don't wear "puff" sleeves, as it is hard
        to sail against tho wind with them.
        Don't wear golf stockings on n long
        journey unless you are seeking martyr
        dom.
        Don't be afraid lo wear "bloomers.
        They have come; tc stay as part of tho
        Wheeling costume.
        Don't go out on a bicycle wearing a
        tail coat unless you enjoy making a
        Xidiculous show of yourself.
        Don't travel without a jacket or loose
        wrap, to be worn while resting. A sum
        mer cold is a stubborn thing.
        Don't allow a taste for a bit of color in
        your make-up to tempt you to wearing
        a red or other gay-colored cap.
        Don't bo harsh in youi criticism of
        "bloomers," as there is no toiling how
        ■oon your best girl may tako to wearing
        them.
        Don't dress immodestly or in tho cos
        tume oi a track sprinter, sweaters worn
        like a Chinaman's blouse are almost in
        decent.

        Lady Norreys. who is one of the patron
        esses of the Trafalgar Bicycle club, wihch
        is to be opened this month, is an enthu
        siastic wheelWOman. .She does not, how
        ever, consider a divided upper garment
        essential, but advocates a tailor-made,
        Shortish skiri, stiffened from the ankle
        to the knee. —Philadelphia Press.

        "There's one tlr'ng about the bicycle
        crazo," said a tailor recently; "I believe
        it is going to revolutionize men's attire,
        which has been fo sombre for so many
        years. I-lress reformers have done mucb
        for women, but men's clothing is practi
        cally tho same year in and year out.
        "The leaders of fashion arc not as a
        rule robust, and the chaps who lead cotil
        lons have small legs. If tbo wheel devel
        ops tboir celves, as it will, I believe the
        age of short clothes will return, and knee
        breeches for evening dress may be seen
        again in drawing rooms, llloomers are
        popular, for a shapely woman likes folks
        to know it. Thin-legged men have a
        chance to build up their calves in sum
        mer for the winter's gayety."
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89067274/1895-07-18/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Hattie+Strage&r=-0.64,0.155,1.643,0.883,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        FINED FOR WEARING TIGHTS
        Chicago, III., July 16. Hattie
        Strage, of 1917 Dearborn street, rode
        over the fashionable South Side boule
        vards Sunday night arrayed in a
        bloomer suit consisting of flesh-colored
        tights and a short jacket. She was
        captured by a policeman and fined 825
        to-day on the charge of being disorderly.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1895-08-25/ed-1/?sp=15&q=BICYCLE+Bicycle+bicycle+Bicycles+bicycles+BICYCLES+bicycling+Costume+costume+COSTUMES+costumes+TAILOR+tailors#viewer-text-image-wrapper</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        PRACTICAL COSTUMES THESE
        During the past few months many de
        signs for a suitable eostumo for women
        to wear when cycling havo appeared in
        the papers. Of these a few wore neat,
        practicable and woarable, but for the
        most part tbe designs were anything but
        practicable. In connection with this ar
        ticle appear six designs which are de
        signed by well-known tailors, and all
        have been tried and found to be as prac
        ticable as they are becoming. We are able
        to reproduce the sketches used in this
        connection through tbo courtesy of Ste
        phens it ffickok, the local agents of the
        Columbia bicycle.
        Costume No. 1 is designed and worn by
        Mrs. Jenness Miller. Mrs. Jenness Miller
        bas given to this suit ths name Colum
        bia, and describes It iv her lectures. The
        suit consists of trousers, designed to look
        as much like a divided skirt as possible,
        hanging trom a sleoveless underwaist,
        thus obviating the need of a belt at the
        waist. The trousers are gathered to n
        band at the knee. Tbe jackot is loose
        and comfortable, with long, full skirt.
        Leggings of elastic clotb reach to tbe
        knee. A cap of neat design completes
        tbe suit.
        Costume No. 2 is by Rcdfern of New
        York and London. It is an extremely
        smart costume, consisting of short skirt,
        worn over knickerbockers of the seine
        material, and waist with vest of red cloth
        and gold buttons under front of light box
        cloth. Leggings of box cloth. Alpine
        bat. The material recommended by Red
        fern Is a rich open tweed.
        No. 3 is a bicycle costume designed and
        Worn by Miss "Georgia Cayvan. This,
        costume consists|nf couave trousers and a
        amort Eton jacket with full sleeves, worn
        over a.shirt which may be either loose or
        close, or a dainty sweater or tight-fitting
        jersey bodico with or without sleeves.
        Around the waist is a bolt of suedo,
        drawn through a buckle. The trousers
        ere made without lining and in light
        serges for summer, a war n lining being
        added for winter wear. Leggings of jer
        rey cloth, when wanted, are worn from
        the shoe to abovo the knee, tho jersey
        cloth being elastic and affording full play
        to the ankles. A sailor hat, with chiffon
        at the side and Mercury wings, completes
        tbe costume.
        No. 4 is another design by Red fern.
        This is the eostumo for bicycling moat
        favored in Franot« It consists of the
        famous bloomers, with Norfolk coat,
        made of dark green tweeds, with collar
        and waistband of green cloth of very deep
        shade fastened by gold buckles. Tho long
        E alters are id slute-colored cloth to match
        at and gloves.
        No. 5 shows a design by OOSta Kraemer
        M New York city. The cost umo consists of
        ti medium plain skirt and a modification
        of the Eton jacket, with a soft roll collar
        and ends falling in front. With it is
        worn a dainty sweater or such waist as
        taste may dictate. The material may bo
        serge, cravenette or any id' the soft Wool
        ens. Legging of jorsey (loth or other
        elastic matorial. with trousers under the
        skirt, nic optional.
        No. fi ,s a second design by Gosta Krae
        mer of New York city. The trousers are
        of aooordton-plaited serge, very full und
        gathered to a band buttoning at the knee,
        or an accordion-plaited skirt may be worn
        Over knickerbockers producing almost tlie
        a same effect. The cout is single-breasted,
        intended to button us shown or to hang
        almost closed when unbuttoned. A sbirt
        waist of wool or silk is worn under the
        coat. Leggings of jersey cloth, when dc
        sirod, complete the costume.

        If a woman.will follow the pursuits of
        a man, will become an equal iv work and
        ambitions, she must have a practical cos
        tume. She cannot wait to grasp her
        skirts if ;sho must grasp a particular car
        railing; she cannot wait for her skirts if
        she must bo at the otiice in timo to begin
        work with her brother. The woman of
        leisure need tukc no part in the demand
        for reform dress, only inasmuch as sho
        choosea to assist her working sister.
        So says Mrs. Russell Sage, whoso opin
        ion is not only valuable because she is
        Mrs. Sage, but equally so as coming from
        a woman who is a careful reasoner.a sym
        pathising sister and one capable of ex
        pressing her views in a manner attractive
        and logical.
        Tho bloomer question was to be the
        subject of my interview, and as I sat on
        tho sofa which Mrs. Sage told mo was ono
        hundred years old, I wondered what tig
        tires of weight and means might be regis
        tered on those springs, and I could not
        lefrain from crushing one blue cushion
        unmercifully,
        Cedarhusrt, L. 1., is the summer home
        of the Sages and tho scene of my inter
        view. Mrs. Sage told me of her home in
        Syracuse, where she knew the real Mrs.
        Bloomer. Mrß. Sage as a girl was Miss
        slocum, daughter of Joseph Slocuin.
        Tho atmosphere of her home at Syracuse
        was entirely conservative. Nevertheless
        when tbe people came to Syracuse to the
        anti-slavery meetings, wnen Dr. Samuel
        May gathered the progressive set about
        him there and Mrs. Bloomer came in
        from Seneca Palls, Mrs. Sage very often
        attendej tne meetings.
        Dr. May was a powerful factor in the
        anti-slavery cause, and Mrs. Bloomer was
        also an abolitionist. She came us a dele
        gate and her costume excited some atten
        tion. Her maimer, us Mrs. Sage remem
        bers her, was unpretentious, quiet and
        delicately feminine. Her costume showed
        a total disregard ior effect, and was man
        ish only to tbe extent of practicability.
        Her bodice was soft and baited at the
        waist, her collar ample and correct, us
        was also ber prim bonnet; ber skirt fell
        halt way from knee to ankle, and then
        the bloomer—really a pantalet—made ol
        tbe same black material as thereat of ber
        costume, reaching to her boot tops.
        In those days pantalets were the vogue,
        and Mrs. Sage smiled as she told me of
        her own favorite pair, with four little
        ruttles, always crimped for Sunday. Mrs.
        Bloomer did not appear too stong-minded
        then, us she only gave up muslin for tbe
        more serviceable matorial. As Mrs.
        Sage so knew Mrs. Bloomer, she agreed
        that she was entirely what sbo aimed to
        be—a practical woman, progressive and
        competent of realizing results from her
        theories.
        Mrs. Miller, n daughter of Gerrit Smith
        of Syracuse, was the next noticeable
        patron of the bloomers, but ber costumes
        were always of handsome black silk.
        "That clock is seventy-live years old.
        Tt was my mother's," said Mrs. Sago,
        pointing to a pretty hanging clock m tbe
        drawing room, "I wind it always myself
        and to do so must step upon tbat table.
        Iv this effort I-rind my skirts dangerous
        us well as inconveniet. Yet I consider
        woman can only afford to sacrilice the
        grace of skirts at the altar of necessity.
        A woman's dinner party would be as
        ordinary aa a club luncheon without the
        added charm of variety of costume. But
        ns v street or walking dress we need a
        uniform which can be worn till worn out
        on every outdoor occasion. This need
        not embrace coat, vest, necktie, etc., but
        should essentially contain all—but only
        all it calls for a comfortable, practical
        walking costume. whether bloomer,
        divided skirt or pantalet, with any femi
        nine variations of which it will reason
        ably admit. On a bicycle, of course, I
        cannot sco how a woman would attempt
        to rid» without the bloomer."—New
        York Herald.

        The new rider is content to go out on
        tho boulevard In long troutien tightened
        at the siiklcs with steel bands, but pro
        ficiency usually brings an abhorrence of
        this inappropriate costume. Many skilled
        bicyclists would rather stay at home than
        he seen riding on Riversiae drive in or
        dinary trousers. Thus the appearance
        of the world on wheels tends to become
        more and more agreeable. Hut many
        queer combinations in clothing are slill
        to be seen. Some of those who wear tbe
        long trousers choose an old pair. Occas
        ionally this garment is so far gonthe fringes at tlie bottom are almost
        rulHles. Perhaps a scarlet j.Tsoy shirt
        and scarlet cap are worn witli the trous
        ers. A part of the ridres consider any
        thing good enough for wheeling, and so
        rig tnemselves out in soiled clothes origi
        nally intended tor tennis, rowing or base
        ball. The flaring colors in their con
        trasts suggest an east side costume ball.
        College oarsmen and football players don't
        want spick and span new uniforms, and
        even take tho trouble to roll in the dirt
        with them to tone them down, but there
        seems no good reason why a man who
        dresses carefully for uuainass should ap
        pear like a scarecrow on his wheel. Tho
        "bicycle stoop" and worn out or inap
        propriate clotniug oftun go together.—
        Now York Tribune.

        In tho discussion of women's cycling
        costumes, too little attention has been
        given to footwear. Upon this fundamen
        tal point practical riders differ, and with
        good reason. They agree that heavy
        stockings, ribbod or smooth, of cotton or
        woolen, are essential, silk hose being ab
        solutely barred by their evident unfit
        ness. The difference is between tlie wear
        ers of low or high ahoss. Tho advocates
        of low shoe claim greaier freedom and
        consequently greater strength for the ank
        les in their costume. Tho believer in
        high shoes says that tbe ankle is protect
        ed from injury and helped to hear tbe
        steady strain by using the high boot.
        Most practical wheelwomen hold the
        opinion that leggings should be worn
        simply for warmth in cool weathor. As a
        rule both the high and low shoe part.es
        wear the pointed toe. The extra length
        of such a shoe is to be considered in rid
        ing, and, like any other superfluity, is
        out of place on the wheel. A shoe with a
        broad toe is much to be preferred for
        both nse and beauty in bicycling.
        A young woman while riding a bicycle
        in Paris the other day came in contact
        with the curb and was thrown to the
        ground. A paper Venetian lantern of
        the kind that is frequently used in France
        in place or the ordinary bicycle lamp set
        rire to her skirts and might have burned
        her badly had not several passers-by as
        sisted in putting out the flames before
        much damage had been done. As she re
        mounted she remarked that the accident
        would not have occurred if she had only
        worn bloomers.—New Yoilc Evening Sun.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1895-10-18/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Annie+bicycle+BLOOMER</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1896-03-14/ed-1/?sp=19&q=bicycle+bloomer+bloomers&r=0.116,0.009,0.649,0.349,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        HE ORIGIN OF THE
        bicycle bloomer is
        not altogether lost
        in the midst of anti
        quity. It is certain
        that one day a young
        lady rider, observing,
        as many had done
        before her, that the
        ordinary skirt is ob
        'jectionable because it
        impedes the free
        movement of the
        legs and is in danger
        of being caught in the
        machineLy, hit upon the simplest and most
        obvious of devices. She reached down in
        front, caught the back edge of her skirt
        between her feet, and pulled it up between
        her knees. The result was a modest and
        practical pair of bloomers while on the
        wheel which instantly fell into the ordinary
        skirt on her descent.
        This discovery may have been made In
        Berlin, London or New York; but in all
        probability it was made in Paris.
        This improvised bloomer is still to be met
        with numerously in Paris, particularly in
        the unfashionable northern, southern and
        eastern suburbs, where holiday afternoons
        are enjoyed with more zest than prepara
        tion. The natural feminine tendency to
        worldliness, luxury and expense, however,
        has effected its substitution by regularly
        made bloomers in the more posing West
        Erid. As a matter of fact in the spring of
        Ibid bloomers have come to stay, though
        they are not called bloomers, but panta
        loons.
        Tourists who get up early enough in the
        morning to take a turn in the Bois at the
        fashionaable hour of 10 a.m. will be repaid
        by the sight of numberless young married
        ladies of the highest fashion apedaling in
        zouaves, with only old-fashioned clubmen
        to mutter at this innovation as at all other
        signs of the times. care no more for the
        park, it's disgusting. Even in the morning
        nowadays it's full of bicyclists and for
        eigners! Look at those costumes! They're
        r~o longer women!" Yet these tight or
        loose-breeched dames are of the Parisian
        -100. They wear pantaloons and ride on
        men's machines.
        Every Kind of Wheel.
        Paris is so complicated in its social or
        ders-like a universe of stars that keep
        their tracks, and yet appear to form con
        stellations-that a passing visitor may easi
        ly be deceived on the bicycle bloomer ques
        tion. The afternoon hurley-burley of the
        Bois, say, near the Avenue of the Grand
        Armee, shows every kind of co:tume, as it
        shows every kind of wheel; and it takes an
        experienced person to separate-not the
        wheat from the chaff-but the various
        grain, the wheat, the rye, the barley, the
        corn and the chaff of each from the mix
        ture. American tourist girls are often hor
        rifled at the costumes they see. They are
        more frequently moved to laughter. The
        truth is that as yet Paris has evolved no
        settled styles in bloomers. Therefore, while
        some err from daring, others err from bad
        judgment, and many more by reasons of
        economy.
        The American girls complain that the
        great majority of the Parisian bicycle
        bloomers are dowdy. It is true, and could
        hardly be otherwise. It must be remem
        bered that the middle-class Parislenne de
        pends on the ready-made gown department
        of the great shops almost as much as the
        American middle-class man depends on the
        ready-made suit industry, which so distin
        guishes our country. And, furthermore,
        the "adaptability" and "elegance" tradi
        tionally ascribed to the Parislenne has
        heretofore always had to do with very fem
        inine and frou-frou types of dress. The or
        dinary Parisienne has not yet achieved the
        real tailor-made gown; and until a recent
        date she would not have desired it. Now
        she runs to the Louvre or the Bon Marche
        for a bicycle costume--and.the whole mat
        ter being new to her, takes docilely what is
        given her.
        When the fashionable dressmakers or
        new-fangled ladies' tailors are called in the
        bloomer4. and waists are apt to be of an ex
        aggerated Scotch or English look, in whch
        all but the most up-to-date worldings of the
        400 find themselves uncomfortable. With
        this there is no mistaking English and
        American girls in the Bois today, bloomers
        or no bloomers. Perhaps it is partly be
        cause French young women are plumper
        to be polite-than our own. For example,
        with them, on the bicycle as off it, the cen
        ter of gravity yields to no dissimilation.
        One is constantly reminded of full moons
        or sofa cushions. What the dressmakers
        achiev'e in the waist they seem to lose be
        low it. The French woman being differ
        ently built from the Anglo-Saxon, both go
        ing and coming, she appears to sprawl more
        in bloomers. She looks queer enough seated
        on the machine, but once she descends ahe
        locks queerer.


        Two other factors enter into the queer
        ness of all the feminine bicycling of Paris.
        The great majority of lady riders are not
        unmarried girls of good society. These lat
        ter may attempt the wheel in the privacy
        of the country, but they do not show in any
        number in the park. In all the classes-the
        aristocracy, the bourgeoisie and the "little"
        bourgeoisie-it is the young married woman
        who pedals. This fact presents an ensem
        ble of maturity to the newly arrived Amer
        ican. Now, what would be luxurious when
        safe guarded by all the artifices of femi
        nine attire, which have stood the test of
        ages, becomes mere ostentation under the
        simplicity of the bloomer, The change for
        the great mass of French lady cyclists has
        been too great.
        Many have seen thin and tried to remedy
        it, both the lighter-minded of the "half
        world" and their more estimable sisters.
        Some-in both categories-have frankly
        taken up men's costumes, loose knicker
        bockers, and longish sack coats. Others
        wear tighlt-knegtlbreeches and fancy jerseys.
        Othersadd t'o tnis a short skirt, reaching to
        the kn s0 'with or without leggings or
        heavy ~cj~ stdekings. For these it is 'any
        thing t~gtai4ty from the organ-grinder
        monke effect "threatened by zouaves or
        bloomem~s.
        in this way t~e accomplish a great deal
        in gracefulness f outline at the expense of
        a very little modety. Speaking simply from
        the standpoint of architecture, bloomers dis
        figure lovely woman by hanging below the
        knees.
        It is almost pitiful to Lee them reveling
        in their new-fotund liberty of costume. They
        would overrun the Parisian promenade did
        not an ordinance of the prefect of police
        forbid the appearance of bicycle costume
        without a bicycle. Recently there was an
        attempt to enforce this mandate strictly,
        and it failed. The only law on which the
        prefect of pollee had to go was that for
        bidding one sex to attire itself in the garb of
        another. A test case provoked a dictum
        from a judge to the effect that bloomers or
        zonaves could not by any possibility be
        looked on as a male costume. Nowadays,
        therefore, so long as the damsels confine
        their promenades en pantalon to the festive
        quarters like Montmartre and the Latin
        Quarter, they are not iholested, being char
        itably supposed to have their wheels some
        where nearby.

        Parisiennes willingly accept what they
        know to be only doubtfully becoming! It in
        a revolution and will have far-reaching re
        sults. Indeed, many see in It the emanci
        pation of the French young girL. The pre
        tuntions upper bourgeoisie is chary of al
        lowing its daughters to ride in pubfle, but
        when the "jeune personne" takes to the
        machine at all it must be in bloomers, like
        her married siter. Apart from these, how
        ever;, a new class has been tapdby the
        machine, the lowersmiddle clswhich
        heretofore ha.= had no res ohanco at spor..
        Living always, habeve 0efortably, In
        cramped a tm t hoq the bicycle
        makes a strong a" to mothers and
        daughters; as well sons igna fathefs.
        The eheapness ot the bicycle and the
        temptations It offers4o these Parisias who
        adore the country all the more because they
        do not often see incline the learts of
        these hondst people strongly to the wheel.
        All 'the world of little employes has wel
        comed the bicycle.cdWith it they get In
        act& touch with q ~untry life, the roads,
        the ,lages. the fiel It Is pleasanter than
        the regulation Sun #y railway trip to sonie
        small town, with iaimless walk around
        provincial streets OgA to a weary wood, to
        sit there blankly, fe ing out of place and
        cramped by city sh. Q and garments, wish
        ing vainly for a ca. e. To all this world
        of commercial emp .lies and government
        clerks independencedimes easy. And there
        are those who think4 ithat twenty years of
        radicalism in the public schools is begin
        ning to show its effept with the thiddle and
        upper-middle bourgeoisie.
        If this movement pontinues, bicycle rid
        Ing may become as-respectable for young
        girls as. for their, married sisters. The
        mothers of the present day may still be very
        much of the old school-lacking its religion.
        And the daughters can scarcely be other
        wise then what they.are, trained up as they
        have teen. Still, rumors of the different
        life of English and American girls; and even
        Germarn girls, come to them, and they won
        der, with derision or regret, as may be. The
        wheel is new. It is fashionable as well as
        Popular. It may bring with it the emanci
        pation of the French young girl. And when
        it does, she will appear in bloomers.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1896-03-15/ed-1/?sp=19&q=BICYCLE+bicycle+drop+frame+ladies+lady</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Mrs. Hj'ifrove Received It Last Week
        for a Bleyele Skirt.
        The palm for a rapid and skillful busi
        ness transaction must unquestionably
        be awarded to the young and pretty
        British matron, Mrs. Bygrave.
        Mrs. Bygrave landed in America on
        Friday, the last day of January, with
        a bicycle skirt of her own invention for
        sale. Within two hours of her arrival,
        while still nervous and dizzy from her
        long and earnest communion with Nep
        tune. Mrs. Bygrave had not only
        denned her new original skirt, but was
        displaying its various merits to the
        buyer of one of the largest sporting
        goods establishments in the country.
        Not satisfied wi.th the offer he made
        her, this self-confident, energetic young
        woman went forth on Saturday in
        search of greater financial inducements
        to part with her cycling skirt. The
        first establishment she visited offered
        her a royalty on all sales made. But
        Mrs. Bygrave had other ambitions and
        walked away in her patent skirt to a
        well-known firm on Twenty third street.
        The wisdom of her, course was shown
        when she promptly received an offer
        of $5,000 from the Twenty-third street
        dealers, who stipulated, of course, that
        they should receive full assurance of a
        patent from Washington. Lest there
        should be any difficulty" in regard to
        the condition of the patent, Mrs. By
        grave on Monday started for Washing
        ton, remained in the patent office two
        hours, found the coast clear for launch
        ing, as it were, the new cycling skirt,
        and returned to New York on the after
        noon train. She did not see the White
        house. That was not her business in
        Washington, she said.
        On Tuesday she visited the patent
        office in New York to make sure that
        there would be no delay in granting the
        patent, visited the firm with whom she
        was negotiating, received a check for
        $500 with a note for the additional sum
        of $4,500 so soon as the patent should be
        received, and on Wednesday morning
        sailed on the Majestic for her native
        shore, the very neat $s,ooo 'transaction
        having been accomplished in less than
        four days. _
        Her cycling skirt is the most novel
        invention in the matter of wheeling
        skirts that has yet come before the
        wheeling public. By a system of cords
        worked through openings near the
        waist line it can be made to fill three
        different varieties of long-felt wants in
        the bicycle woman.
        First of all, it is a trim, circular
        walking skirt, close fitting over the
        hips and measuring about three yards
        at the hem. To adapt this skirt to the
        "drop frame" bicycle* the middle of the
        front breadth is pulled up by means of
        a shirring string run down the front
        seam between the lining and a narrow
        casing. This string is. drawn through
        an opening at the i waist, where' it is
        fastened by means of a clasp under a
        neat pocket flap. The shirring reaches
        a short distance above the knees, leav
        ing the skirt neat and smooth fitting
        about the hips and actually forming
        two loose bags In which the knees
        work up and down without the slight
        est dragging and pulling at the waist
        line, which is the sad -and daily ex
        perience of the woman wearing the or
        dinary skirts.
        The third -possibility of the unique
        garment is developed by working the
        cords that run up the back seam and
        find an outlet under a tailor-made flap
        just over the hip. The pulling of these
        two side cords converts the skirt into
        a pair of neat and graceful bloomers
        that Will permit the fair rider, in case
        of an emergency, to mount a "diamond
        frame" bicycle with all the grace and
        agility of a masculine wheelman. By
        the use of four square leads in the hem
        of the skirt the instant the strings are
        unclasped and the rider stands erect
        the bloomers again become a walking
        skirt. There is no pulling of the gar-
        ment into shapes or adjusting of belt
        necessary. Simply press the clasps
        and the act of dismounting does the
        rest.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024442/1896-06-21/ed-1/?sp=11&q=30+bicycle+bicyclers+bicycles+bicycling+Washington</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        A MARYLAND BOY.
        Policeman J times A. Duvall is a sporty,
        handsome looking young man In bis natty
        bicycle costume, including golf stockings
        and a nobby looking little cap. Heis twenty
        nine years of age, and was born In Prince
        George county, Md., near Upper Marlboro.
        Mr. Duvall has rcsldedin Washington pleven
        years, but gained his schooling In Prince
        George. He is married, and has two Inter
        esting children. He has been on the police
        force five jeurs. and served in the Second,
        Third and Eighth precincts.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-07-09/ed-1/?sp=6&q=bicycle+BICYCLE+women+WOMEN&r=0.16,0.687,0.664,0.415,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Now, a true woman does not compro
        mise her modesty a whit more on the
        bicycle than she does riding on a street
        car or a buggy. All things are evil to the
        evil-minded.
        It so happens that a great many women
        use the bicycle for convenience. They
        have to go from place to place on legiti
        mate business, and it ia quite as proper
        to go on a bicycle as it is to walk. Then
        very many women ride the bicycle for
        health and others for pleasure, and if
        there be anything; immoral in it it is dis
        covered by others than those who ride
        wheels. It ia very true that some women
        bicycle riders adopt costumes that might
        be spliced out a little with the same kind
        of material, but the same is very much
        more true of some men bicyclists. The
        fact is, these are not the days of the May
        flower, but there are just as many good
        and true women now as there were in
        those days. The members of the Rescue
        League might better attend to rescuing
        their own minds from the many unfounded
        suspicions which appear to keep them in a
        etate of agitation.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1942-09-06/ed-1/seq-57/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=bicycle+fashion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=bicycle+fashion&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Autos have vanished and
        bikes are scarce in Paris.
        So this old contraption of
        Gay Nineties vintage serves
        this Parisian model for a
        display of her robe-culotte
        bicycle fashion in a style
        show in the German-occu
        pied former French capital.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020422/1942-05-14/ed-1/seq-6/#date1=1756&index=1&rows=20&words=bicycle+fashion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=bicycle+fashion&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Society has adopted costumes both simple and sensible for the popular and healthful sport of bicycle rid
        ing. These, worn by the Misses Sally Gardiner, daughter of Mrs. Henry Gardiner of Princeton, N. J* Gen
        evieve Kenntz, spending the winter at the Golf and Tennis ©lub, Palm Beach, Fla., and Gene McGlynn,
        with Metro Pictures, Hollywood, show the bicycle fashion trends for spring, all with costumes which per
        mit freedom of action. Shorts seem to be the choice of the majority, Including all male observera.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84038095/1909-04-07/ed-1/seq-22/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=bicycle+bicycle-fashion+fashion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=bicycle+fashion&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85035722/1897-06-12/ed-1/seq-2/#date1=1756&index=3&rows=20&words=bicycle+fashion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=bicycle+fashion&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        If his wheel distracts his mind from
        the object he is trying to attain he
        gives his opponent just so much ad
        vantage which he otherwise would not
        have. So what it really amounts to
        is that the man who wishes to fight his
        duel on a bicycle must leave the man
        agement of his wheel to his feet and
        knees.
        The combatants in a mock duel of
        this nature are dressed in the ordinary
        outing costume of the cyclist. Their
        hands are clothed in gauntlets. ’ The
        stockings worn are usually faced with
        a very fine quality of chamois skins.
        The shoes are of the regulation bicycle
        fashion, with rubber soles.
        On the inner side of the trousers,
        just above the point where the leggings
        and the bottoms of the trousers meet,
        is a round piece of rubber about an
        eighth of an inch thick and seven and
        one-half inches in circumference. The
        object of this rubber is to give the
        rider a firm pressure upon the ma
        chine, just as the rubber soles of his
        shoes act as a safegmird^againgt, his
        feet slipping on the pedals.
        Each duelist wears a mask which
        has over each eye a projection of wire,
        similar in form to a small inverted
        tea cup. This gives absolute freedom
        of vision.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1901-08-04/ed-1/seq-44/#date1=1756&index=4&rows=20&words=bicycle+fashion&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=bicycle+fashion&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-charlie-chaplin/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045487/1915-11-04/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Charile+Chaplin+Charley&r=-0.402,0.117,1.735,0.933,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        PASTORS CANT COMPETE WITH
        CHARLEY CHAPLIN
        Milwaukee, Nov. 4. "Charlie
        Chaplin" sermons were called "im
        possible" by the Rev. Samuel H.
        Woodrow of St Louis in speaking be
        fore the Woman's Board of Missions
        of the Interior, which closed here to
        day. "There has been much talk about
        making sermons interesting," said
        the speaker. "We never can make
        sermons as interesting as melo
        dramas or prayer meetings as amus
        ing as Charlie Chaplin. They never
        were meant to be so.
        "If a heathen dropped into New
        York and saw a church with a seating
        capacity of 1,500, attended by about
        200 on Sunday and dark six days a
        week, he would never go back with
        the impression that the United States
        was a Christian nation."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085187/1916-03-10/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Charile+Chaplin+Charley</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Charlie Chaplin is going
        to get $87 0,000 this year for
        making a fool of himself.
        And just think of the num
        ber of would-be ball tossers
        who do the same thing for
        nothing every training sea
        son.

        Charlie Chaplin, highest paid
        actor in the world, is appearing
        at the Melbourne and Liberty to
        day in the same picture, "His
        First Vacation.'' Never before
        has the same actor appeared in
        the same picture at two Tacoma
        movies at the same time.
        It is an evidence of the keen
        rivalry between movie men. The
        Melbourne had signed the film
        for next week. The Liberty, how
        ever, obtained the same picture
        for the latter half of this week.
        Manager Sumni**rville of the Mel
        bourne telegraphed a hurry-up
        order for his film yesterday when
        he heard of the Libertys' move,
        and obtained his copy of tlie film
        by express yesterday. He put it
        on his bill at 4 p. ni. without an-
        Tlie picture remains at both
        houses until tomorrow night.
        CHAPLIN AT
        LIBERTY
        The old favrolte Charlie
        Chaplin—who has returned to
        the IJberty.
        Movie fans who see Charlie
        Chaplin this week at the Liberty
        will not only see the world's
        greatest comedian in action, after
        a long vacation, but will witness
        the work of a man who gets
        $670,000 a year for being foolish.
        Chaplin recently signed with Mu
        tual at this price. His Liberty
        film, "His First Vacation," is
        added to the regular bill of "The
        Innocence of Ruth,' a clever
        ;crook drama.

        "Via Wlreles," with Galli
        1 Kane and Bruce MrKae, and J
        "Hlii First Vacation," with r
        Charlie Chaplin.
        LIIIRHTY
        "The Imnocence of Itut!i."&lt
        with Viola Dana, and "Hi-
        Flmt VacaUon," with Chafici
        Friday. March 10,1916,,
        Charlie Chaplin lias tlie honor
        of appearing at two bin Pacific
        avenue photoplay houses today
        and tomorrow in the MUM pic
        ture—a feat never before accom
        plished in Tacoma by any motion
        picture actor.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093407/1916-04-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Charile+Chaplin+Charley+March+Parade</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Charlie Chaplin* Give Down
        town Seattle Lunch
        time Laugh
        THEY'RE LED BY BAND
        The downtown aection of
        Seattle waa all messed up with
        Charlla Chapllna Saturday
        noon.
        About 300 boys, all coatum
        ad Ilka Charlie and Imitating
        I th* ecrean comedian'a famous
        walk, participated In Tha
        Star*a Charlie Chaplin parada.
        Tom North, Northweat minuir
        of tfc* film led
        profession la his automobile Then
        nm» Cavana'itha band, and then
        the rarortlnn Chaplin*
        Other automohllrs brouaht up
        the rear, one of them rirrylii* the
        Judaea
        Th»re were Chaplin* of all a»e*
        and aires, from boya of 5 rlear up
        the line.
        f'rlrea were awarded at Iton
        March* park, at the conclusion of
        the parade
        N'orman Hsrkett. leidln* man
        i for Wlike* player* at th«&gt Metro
        i&gtolHan. Mavor'a Secretary Jlmmv
        I 'rehan. li. S Tolila*. of the North
        ern Pacific, Tom North and John
        liamrli'k were Judaea
        Klrat prlite $25 In ca*h.
        given by INmrlck. who I* man
        ager of the It**. where Chaplin'*
        burleaque on "Carman" I* now br
        ine shown Second prl»e wa* a
        125 watch. glv»n by Tom North
        Third prlte wan a 125 *ult of
        clothe*. given by Channcey Wright.
        Other prlaea of Rei pa**ea were
        given
        Ttio i!»t of prlre winner* will b*
        anrmnn'ln Monday'* Star
        The only red-beaded Charlie
        Chaplin In the world *i» dlacov
        ered In thr parade
        ll« had clipped a wlap of hi*
        own brick-colored tre**e* and paet
        ed them on hla upper lip.
        During the performance at the
        Hon Marehe park, one future
        oon a year comedian lost hla baggy
        trouaera while doing the Charlie
        Chaplin walk
        The kla went In drove*
        They *w*tted eali other ov«r
        the hrada and made face* nt the
        truffle cop*
        One cnterprl*itig Charlie crawled
        on the back of n pn*alng anto and
        Rwatted an elderly occupant over
        the "dome" with hi* cane
        Daylight bomb* containing tlck
        eta to the Metropolitan theatre
        were explodod In the »lr before
        the parade.
        </text>
      </result>


      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014682/1917-10-15/ed-2/?sp=5&q=Charile+Chaplin+Charley+Reel&st=text&r=0.32,0.423,0.469,0.485,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Charlie Chaplin the real one may
        remain in Honolulu for a short time,
        but Charlie Chaplin the reel one is
        almost a permanent fixture. Provided
        the management of the Hawaii thea
        ter can s'o arrange, C. C. will be a
        perpetual attraction.
        There is little difference with C. C.
        as to the title of his attractions. Just
        so long as the leading comedian of
        the screen is in the billing Honolulu
        and every other city in the world will
        turn out almost en masse. i ne cur
        rent Chaplin attraction at the Hawaii
        happens to be entitled "The foreman,"
        and the title is a good one as it is
        an excuse for Chaplin himself to ap- j
        near for a couple of reels of laugh J
        production. As is customary with
        Chaplin's films there is nothing to it
        but laughter, although that commo
        dity is more plentiful than at any time
        at the Hawaii since, the last appear
        ance of the same star.
        Lillian GIsh also appears as a .Ha
        waii star in. "An Innocent MagdeleneV.
        a strong rnangie-r me ah imiuic
        This Is one of the Hawaii favorites.

        CHARLIE CHAPLIN, AND
        SAILS AWAY FOR HIL0
        Boyishly beaming with satisfaction
        at the great crowd present, Charlie
        Chaplin reeled up the gangway or the
        Mauna Kea Saturday afternoon before
        departing for his visit to the volcano.
        Minus his makeup, "moustache.
        i
        cane ana massive snoes, some ui
        the many children present could not
        be convinced that their screen idol
        had really come to life in Honolulu
        until the comedian twisted his ears,
        wrinkled his face and let his feet per
        form. Then there was a chorus of
        childish voices shouting, "bee Char
        Hot"
        lib
        Cliarlie had scarcely boarded the
        steamer until lfe and Demosthenes
        Lycurgus had established an entente
        and posed with arms locked for a
        squad of amateur photographers. Due
        to "Monty's" plentiful proiwrtions
        there was grave danger of the Vol
        cano hotel manager "hogging the
        camera," until Charlie was placed on
        the weather, or camera, side.
        As the Mauna Kea pulled into thqi
        stream, the screen comedian waved
        a red bouquet, tiped his white flan
        nel hat, shuffled three dance step3,
        did a" donkey" with his cars, smiled
        his Roosevelt smile, teeth and all,
        and shouted "Aloha kakou."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058246/1917-11-15/ed-1/?sp=6&q=Charlie+Chaplin</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        CHARLIE CHAPLIN
        IN HAWAII
        HONOLULU, Nov. 12. Tho fam
        ous Charllo Chaplin arrived in Hon
        olulu, October 10, and whllo ho in
        tended to como for a rest betweon
        custard pio throwing contests, ho
        waa'kept cxtromely busy sightseeing.
        Photographers camped on his trail
        and snapped him riding tho sivf
        boards on tho Beach at Wnlkl, eat
        ing two fingered pol, dancing with
        tho hula girls and even flirting with
        Polo, tho Goddess of Fire, on the
        odgo of tho Volcano at Kllauoa.
        It Is expected that ns soon as his
        contracts permit ho will bring over
        a company and bo filmod with an
        Hawaiian setting which will bo uni
        que. Ho was accompanied by Itobort
        Wagner, tho well known writer and
        they returned to tho mainland, Oc
        tober 17, tired, but happy.
        Charlie Chaplin, movlo king, small
        boys loud his praises sing. Ho will
        bo back with us today from a trip
        to Hllo bay hero ho went to visit
        Pelo and to see tho lnva Jolly. Char
        llo likes Hawaii's stylo and ho fain
        would stay awhllo, loafing on tho
        sun kissed sand, eating pol with
        cither hand; Hstonlng to tho ukuolo
        played by Walkikl, 13111 Dalloy; oat
        Ing.dog in guiso of pig; practising
        thb hula Jig. Dut no's got to get
        back home and with us may" no
        moro roam back to make a nation
        smile In raro Charlie Chaplin's way.
        When his pictures come this way
        as they will on some flno day, wo
        shall watch for something new In
        the moving scenic vlow. Wo shall
        hope His Nibs to see In tho surf at
        Walkikl, look to see him gaily prance
        in tho featlvo hula dance, and find
        Joy without alloy, in tho palo elus
        ivo pol, Charlie Chaplin's back to
        day. Hip hurray! Banzai! Hurray!
        We shall seo him, I've a hunch at
        the merry Ad Club's lunch, where
        ho'll pick a friendly bone and make
        Jokes to help tho Loan.
        Now, togethor, small boys all old
        boys, bold boys, short or tall, when
        the boat pulls out tomorrow show
        your very earnest sorrow that C Q.
        has got to go, that .,tho parting is
        a blow, by parading to tho boat there
        to take a final gloat at tho moving
        picture king; hark, the herald angels
        sing!
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1918-11-12/ed-1/?sp=13&q=Charile+Chaplin+Charley+Bride</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        "When I wanted to marry I didn't
        have tho money. Now thut I havo
        tb.3 money, I don't care to marry."
        Theffo wcrt) once Charles Spencer
        Chaplin's sentiments, but elnco ho
        mado that remark tho same Mr.
        Chaplin, who Is Charilo .Chaplin,
        Charlie of tho films, tho llttlo fellow
        who lias made millions laugh at Ills
        queer shoes and ridiculous mustache,
        and, Incidentally, has mado millions
        of. dollars for himself, lias been in
        ducted Into the ranks of tho bene
        dicts by charming Miss Mildred J
        Harris, another screen star, of Loa
        Angeles.
        Tho woolnff under a bunch of
        "Coopers" Instead of a moon was
        all kept very secret, and his most
        intimate friends were as surprised
        as any one else when tho news was
        mado public recently that Charlie
        and Mildred had slipped quietly away
        to th houso of R. S. Sparks, head
        of tho Loa Angeles County Llcensa
        Bureau, and had been married by
        the Rev. James L Meyers,,
        Tills all happened ns far back as
        Oct S3, but they successfully kept the
        newo to themselves until recently Mr.
        Sparks let tho cat out of tho bag when
        he laughingly remarked that Charilo J
        would liavo to work overtlmo now!
        that ho had a wlfo to support. When
        questioned further Mr. Sparks con
        firmed tho story of the marrlago and
        added:
        "Mr. Chaplin did not want any c.v.
        awiuciu muuo over me mamaga. no
        told mo that unless It could bo kept
        very quiet ho would go to soma other
        county seat for a license. It would
        never havo dono to let Charilo Chup
        lln go to any other placo than Los
        Angeles, so I did my best to keep
        things as quiet as possible."
        Tho girl bride, for .Miss Harris Is
        only seventeen years old, has the
        ability to throw an appealing, chnrm
        Into her picture, work, and Will bo re.
        membcred by movlo .fans for this
        quality In "Tho llrldo of tho South,"
        in which aho appeared.
        Charles Chaplin was born In Lon
        don in 1830, and Ills first appearance
        on tho stage was with' his parents
        when ho was eight years old in "Krotn
        Itags to ltlclios," which tnust have
        been an omen of gooll luck, for tho
        last pari of tho title of that llr.it play
        has certainly como truo with lilra.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1920-08-29/ed-1/?sp=29&q=Funny+Charlie+Chaplin&st=text&r=0.238,0.559,0.401,0.431,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        C60k .Chaplin in a Care-Free, lay a
        havng Just the Way He Did Noa
        Says, So F as Sbe Was CoS
        rcent case of bgoken romance and
        once fond hearts estranged has cre
        ated such interest as the .st for
        divorce by Mrs. Charlie Chaplin against
        her husband. the world famous funny. man
        5t the motion pictures. The cbarges
        brought by Mrs. Chaplin are "mental ers
        .t and failurs of her husband to riovide
        for her. $1
        Among the millions whord Charlie Chap.
        tin has made laugh there 1rye rrobably
        een many. who have thoug.M lw care
        free and amusing the lot of the woman
        was his wife. No woman. It would
        could ever have the blun 'off be
        'ng but cheerful with so m!rth.
        L a companion. Yqt strangely
        cr-e are no sadder, more pea31
        't than the professional humor6
        to to use up all their store of
        :ir output. And, acpording to
        Charlie Cha lin 17 no ex
        I she tAils Wat she alleges
        1 l:AIdi story of her life with the
        t on earth-so far as the
        Scancerned.
        ir iin has denied' all that Mrs.
        ebarges in her suit, and has a;
        d 'bha, elf as being much su rid'
        d c'aon to force tIe issue. Ite will,
        ,ait, bring counter suit against her on
        i vnnccz of his own, and Incidentally al
        i ges that, despite her charge of penury,
        lie spent over $00,000 in about eightef
        months in housekeeping expenses., al
        though during that time Mrs. Chaplin her
        self was earning $1,000 a week.
        By Mr&. Charlie Chaainn.
        (In as interview)
        A31 quite ready to admit that 'my mar
        riage to Charlie Chaplin was a mistake.
        It was a mistake on es part, because
        he is a genius, and geniuses should not
        %nary. He would better be free and re
        ipain free, for he will make any nwoman he
        marries miserable, I know.
        We have been married for three years.
        For two of those years we lived under the'
        sam~s roof, more or less. That is, if greet
        lng a husband after long disappearances
        might be saiG to be living under f~e same
        roof with him.
        If lying awake, weeping and wondering
        where your husband is, until 4 or 5 #elock
        in the morning can really 'be called living.
        If wrangling over every bill that comes
        'in can be called Mving.
        If living on the scale of an income of
        $260 a week, when your husbat4A earns
        $1g,000 a week, can be called living.
        If having your wardrobe censored and a
        atandard of two or three dressad one
        hat established may be considered an es
        .istence.
        If being told to keep your head down
        t o that no man will'spe your face Is living.
        If hearing that meat and potatoes and
        i dding are enough for a meal and that
        I e cream and salads are silly and useless
        airlly stands for proper living.
        1being constantly accused of diirtinlg by
        a i'n who is causelessly jealous is living.
        this and more I endured--and fo'r
        v.n. vnmonths. That Is the reasoma I heal
        411.e to say that we lived under the same
        !R wasn't living. It was 96Eita
        it ha been said that a comedis is enly
        I 'zay in public I believe It. In fact. I
        :n.w It. Charlie Chaplin, ho 4bs, snaS
        mitIlons laugh, oaly caused. teeiB.
        So It was better that w9'hbodd searate.
        'etter that there be a diveros. E. a
        se him since my~ asit hr beaa
        We met inthe e ice of my in~
        Anel. we parted he said? ifldred ye
        are uight. I should a ave -ted
        I knew it now. -Ton marry
        Ssoon. If you do Ihope vlbe hsWp.
        I ,slnever mar ."a4 we
        loobid at each oiler saafinnnaa
        an is wife.
        Tltthe peblie may a be Ueisd by
        an Iteb6tel fe e
        ==his wife err.
        or -D
        "Meuta
        chali
        Little
        hot even
        He th
        rageous.
        adon't ne
        captured
        I used
        *pretty I
        ought to
        lord of c
        Heod&
        agan 1
        He fdth
        Mr. Chaplin and I met at the home of For this
        y aunt at the. beech, near Los Angelos. He invel
        was 'steying with my aunt. Mr.' Chaplin his 'sketc
        ad! others wore ee~fag. At onc00 he be- work of
        sine attentive. We used to go for long ing, at 1
        ralks on the beach. He talked about his house ot
        if, He told me he 'ras very lonely. He. fear, as
        aid he needed a home and someone to of name)
        are for him. Older and ylser persons, say walk the
        hat kind of tkisa prellde to apro0posal. Heowl
        t was in this case. We "went together." in the u
        a country folks say, for fou months. We he was
        ere marrie4. We went to live in a bit, for his
        oely house on a high hill, Laughlin Bill. was ini
        Losn Angeles., .of thoug
        At ence began the woos of a funny man's He a
        rife-the regpt mental eruelty of which frig*4a.
        comligainq when I brought my s4u4 fe' weeks.
        lvorce. Althogh I was inarried,~ tis.1 lefill
        outh had not game etof met with my o- I msee
        eptafce of, the edigrm.I as not there ww
        ~rvoous, but I em young. Y IR to damee be wl
        ad to be with people. gleny
        Mt. Chaplin .didn't. He Wpuid never e I
        lanc except to keep t ress dasklg- se
        witA other aen. lie like pap al
        t least, not pile who Jo'w tO lad a but b
        ig anEdas use they are'glad thoy wo614 ri
        re aflve.'N- brought me. home to din- and w
        But suck ment Old,Lgrate lac
        etal meet They wers *tty oWE 3dt8
        w mows. They' talked of thtugs 'I este VMg q
        et 'pwbundefttuaate, I w~r seventeiu. e s
        Wat eciWI hak ofo e .W
        reare cme ese~ei or was o o
        He liked to tbtuVh' .hea a Soetatist, literay
        ikogh he dMa't iv. 'like en. He wasn't ambiti
        .ilni.- to atlie hi. moser with apyome, tnant 11
        a Two Picures elf
        with hpiif, Who was ingial
        I Cupekon bild day.uet
        gt-my billTwor dretsses out- dqso itl
        h aid:FYousarestarried. You
        Ibepsivce ed rid.iYu hae
        me. be seriour..H
        lothes to1keeptou.pMartiage
        not even dietsn Iehadslost hi
        with ahws ing hiws inarnion.~.~gcet
        teis a oobda ,I ofe.
        t hiy biwn char dss writs aqC 1
        e said: acts are thmTarri the a imi
        o orxtese des.lse Yo stavey-. ic gu
        me wit ame iour big,.__oady
        the toll heet you co aelnge ith r ndcll m
        ba hinnc o ver nd ro the darkofafrai
        srheats. ates nitghtnc
        whdas lways osig hiantion euheis. o6
        trig e s loo king cfrtyes, h ale e
        seekisng characte ad witeas Atmhhslf n hu
        meadie s ntheemed tiore f r ie ytb a
        o worid the was. ntea of hsta- olrlhdnodee he
        a cd oers the ark afiait woe.oewaurrsr
        os te ns hld e hoe wotfortday tand iarsoeciaet
        Hestdnith friendsdbhpot SAndh
        ter, aswo mavehs, t wa whenIvha h mnwomIh
        rdinorg. Hewaulinge fobstyess ueIke i p o
        seingtb caractrsanromaeiam.ndI Thli~g~I.twh
        I omiaebles and eme thoretI tathmo wth lmI g
        a he worrd d Iwaeowahs woherorqt~stdOR
        lit.ely ascogs .n 6h business.
        e, tao vh oeand isi o uffesthem.solas
        a'Rewud s gae ftar anHhlealn or om
        ad toed wih foind aft 80k mrigeh wudsa
        lefo inwi mths. I rath. wat whe
        e divorce DuCrinbae toedme, aet Ot~ii55O
        ul( ot a oo rea thi em. "ep orba dw.?d
        bI medi back odhresume thetoseyu o. Oh
        hsn ehdely 'tO&MU.~Io
        to itd thea4 e ropsseed
        ad tose ooa too m yTher hate n ado e ace
        m~dInsi tM eathm. Obati semlyofh dsad
        s. Re- watsto ae ofe the elwi hemenn
        I reed t anU Ieer I it eOI
        IbIS'~ *~Idtalkto hm ot th. ta ee bia oa h
        d ~elhs ~budhehadelynex omdas he. wants
        is bm~sig ~ftemt y lodibes.bl he ed toe re54
        a bok. Tere a~he ase tabfgic "ts o
        p~ee~' Ad ye Mr.chapin Chaptlinote as 1 iaet!or
        is N. weat to leavIf the insesBaguisty~so
        iti wlk ndthebagy'tr~ s treek mu.~e W.nd I
        I.
        I
        V.
        A
        'I
        I'
        p i
        %t~
        uina~i
        A R~

        .cI
        rhts were so
        idly jealous.
        red as mine
        waz gre wing
        iwn Aie beat
        ~5fl L did not
        I~. thought
        ould hot be
        4 knOwn be
        my si~it@iS.
        ~tobettsv9
        med contracts Mae. cbapl
        umrd.d mae
        it was born. His leell
        iad$Iir our SasUOd to change. He gi
        me wbi1~ we t@r5~t to n~e. He went
        we dihbag:- mateilal. His room at ti
        'was ay empty. H. did hot even
        s 'would ~iy: from the hospital to our b
        111, t~k ~ou I S5i*t~~ moring dci
        rsbd m~i~mg leasE? house 01 the hUt
        i ~inIs.u eMIL We moved down t
        ~iu Uesume he lAft me alone
        *Mh 'beet to ~'ewk inthe studk
        'Ill Ire t~ like a madman. We 414 n
        sash othe~ toward the l..I
        P095 diveSt *to uay~bedauas We could
        I La the hoe -vftslthsinee.
        teek, a rw~ I Ilk. Smestic IIfV
        ms~bobeuiaL
        i wit.,, m spending none
        ~st when I t.Id him that
        a were beak- bapy toguther sad taIks
        me dsp's eUIdr he oliprud me P6.950. TI
        heGrethe Sa&
        igW r 0sWhich
        *vkcedHer Ta~
        Pictre Comic
        Star IsOnly
        e Half of One Pe
        ltea aHusband
        1
        ino hVfteLk ttega~ ot
        las Agele1
        Igtwr e nta iha h ai hns u h
        p.mr ni- swrha eatamlin
        isa. frthe bik byt Laken mat eve hapn Amerian
        igcus was meotasd wiho s the publyc tonks ue .er
        ew mxored iste. oth atlestnmd.in
        iwa ollctn I wen gean tomen re one hre pe ent
        e. Ahoea was ahs. an lbesethy are do or frid
        elt tak me hto an cno rds M alni eis
        iw. W hal itl done h a nt bee a d e tunncrytan oe
        no agree thea by a funy antt enanAeriaon
        becanee a r. Asia whousb d the nl one-hundred onr
        Mr Chpir ste cent n.
        so mock I wes ambriti en is loe thatre pof ce nt
        La.u as e was. husands Hecantse thaey are moilloin dsl
        t tal mke ito.-lr and tae. Ir halin e aonten ih.
        re hod nott lha be es lad thoe. .tnies 1antor
        o are separton 'Atht oAs way paoetrteaner htagea dis-o
        par.aa whi t anhesadb sue-af n
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1920-12-19/ed-1/?sp=36&q=Charile+Chaplin+Charley&st=text&r=-0.221,-0.072,1.443,1.443,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Charlie Chaplin in CI
        I T was n odd match when the news
        leaked out that Charlie Chaplin, fun
        niest comedian in the motion picture
        world, had married Mildred llarris whose
        film specialty is tears, "sob stuff." And
        the news of the marriage 'was soon follow
        ed by whispers that the funny man bride
        groom was not getting on very well with
        the tearful bride.
        Nobody seemed to know jti~t what was
        the matter but in due time Mrs. Chaplin
        admitted that she and her husband had
        separated. Then followed several state
        ments from Mrs. C'haplin but no comments
        came ifom Mr. Chaplin.
        At last the 'matrimonial troubles drifted
        into the Los Angeles courts. Mrs. (Chap
        Iun brought suit for divorce. And here on
        this page is the sworn testimony given by
        Mildred liarris Chaplin in support of her
        plea for a divorce. Mr. Chaplin did, not
        tak9 the trouble to appear at the trial and
        Ch lie (Chaplin's version of the matter is
        not on record.
        W~hen the case was called recently be
        fore Judge York Mrs. Chaplin took the
        ..uness stand in her own behalf. Ii.
        tt
        IoyMod
        boy efMouscoedan
        DIRECT EXAMINATION.
        QUESTION BY LAWYER GILBERT.
        State your namd in full, please.
        ANSWER BlY MRS. MILDRED HARRIS
        CHIAPLN-Mildred Harris Chaplin.
        QU'ESTION.-How old are you, Mrs.
        Chaplin?
        ANSWER-Nineteen.
        Q.-How long have you been living in
        California?
        A.---Since I wgs seven years old.
        Q.-When were you married?
        A.-October 23, 1918.
        Q.--When did you and Mr. Chaplin be
        come separated, finally?
        ,A.-A year ago this comigg February.
        Q.-Were there any children by this
        marriage?
        A-One boy.
        Q.-ls it living or dead?'
        A.-Dfead.
        (Q -You say you were married when you
        j s.eneen years of ae?
        fred Harris's Si
        that time
        A.-My other
        Q.-idsh kep oucostatl4ude
        her cre?
        A. hed
        Q-twstecureo odc
        whc ormte urudtwr o n
        had a teahe for me
        Q.-Wht ha bente gnraod
        tio ofyu.hat veic, hte
        wasdnot ver srong whenI wS marr
        Q.--u mn byChaplouhaenee
        A.-Yes.
        Q.-tutimrs teamn twr
        A.-Mey moteetadr ey.oey
        Q.-How ohd keep yo. Cnhapnt uthe
        tihe arr d ou
        Q.-You aege ourse coanuta
        whicthe yourstero pfurse toard yofter
        yoawre argryand yarraeduatkep
        an mterst. A twhoae kugetinnastht
        A-Mor. Chadawanen'mst
        Q.-Dliad hated io ny meason fiur.
        whn accoun twlv proesoldrao and te
        her areacohe for nom areo.el e
        Q.-Yout aeen your comgena ad
        fiour ofks you heaheve sie. whithspl
        ofv lnever bnter riblypr stron. aut el
        thae hadr abu fe thelaotl. esbt ee
        veryserous foutridek, of perhaet fever.le
        was, notery wetwrn mared I was arre.
        Q.-Dyou go? ythtyuhaebe
        A.-Yes.
        Q.-Yuu t hern ,te mrrag became
        A -Veryseta.vr oey
        irprising Stor3
        e Famous Fihn
        R4
        LMOST
        flattered
        wife of
        could sle hope i
        pects--such a ric
        fagnous husband
        And such fun i
        dian around the'
        half a dollar or
        for half an hou
        his fun making,
        have him all to I
        Think of it!
        To be the bri
        man in the worlk
        ing till night, to
        his stunts in her
        Would he hoo
        ankle with that
        squash pie in hei
        the door on h
        friends wondere
        to-be was sure I
        the rough stuff
        little wife. Of c
        id
        Charlie.
        Q.--Now. after the marriage becam4
        public. Mrs. Chaplin, just tell the court ii
        ~nur own way about the course of treat.
        ment Mr. Chaplin adopted toward yoi
        after that time?
        A.--Well, after I was taken out of thi
        hospital I had to stay in bed until Christ
        mas, Christmas Eve, and the doctor sent
        a nurse home with me, and Msr. Chaplli
        got us a home up in 4,aughlin Park, and
        lad (po stay in bed until Christmas Eve
        and that was the first tim9 I was dowil
        after I got out of the hospital. .And
        (Christmas afternoon-! mean the day be
        fore Christmas, Mr. Chaplin told me that
        he would be home and have dinner with
        me and help me trim the Christmnas tree,
        and I had had mother get all the Christ.
        man presents. I was not able to get ui
        and I had always thought a great deal of
        Chirstmas, and- that evening. I dressed and
        went downstairs and waited for him, and
        hIe did( not come home. And I waited until
        11 o'clock. and he did not come, so I trim.
        med the tree and mother helped me and
        then I went to bed and stayed awake unti
        about two or tlpree, and Mr.' Chaplin came
        hiome about three o'clock.
        Q.--What occurred?
        A --And when he came home he came
        utpstairs and was very angry at me for
        b'uyirig so many Christmasapresents and
        making~ such a time lover Christmas.
        Q.-Then what occurred?
        A-Then the next day was C'hristmam
        D~ay, and he would '?ot get up all Christmna'
        morning, and I went downstairs and took
        him uip his presents and he was very angry
        at me for making so much over Christmas.
        Q.-What would he say? What did hi
        bay?
        A.--Well, he said it was very foolish
        and that he did not believe in such thing'
        and that I should not be so silly over
        C'hristmas and over having presents and
        liking such things.
        Q.-Now, then, you allege that after that
        Christmas evening he began a course of
        conduct toward you of absenting himmell
        frum home. Tell the court about that.
        A-In February the doctor said I had to
        go up to Mt. I owe for my health. I kepi
        of Her Domes
        Comedian WI
        scent Divorce
        iford from Mr.
        on His Side of
        ny young woman would be Harris a
        to be invited to become the Last Oct
        Charlie Chaplin. Where twenty-i
        o find more attractive pros- The a
        ;h, amiable, entertaining and Judge 7
        as he was certain to be? story of
        to have this inimitable come- part of I
        house! If it was well wortl; divorce.
        nore to sit in a tleatre chair lin woul,
        -and watch "photographs of. of a br
        what would it be worth to after th
        terself all the time? What a
        Charlie
        de of the merriest, funniest Christn
        1! All day long, from morn- Some zi
        have Charlie Chaplin doing And i
        6wn home. -but th
        k her around the neck or her ed that
        busy cane of his, or land a own woi
        face at dinner time, or slam testimo
        er fingers? Miss Harris's low on I
        d about that, biut the bride. s Unfer
        he comedian would cut out was not
        at home and with his own made hil
        ourse he would I So Mildred it to the
        getting wors And worse and I couldn't
        eat, so the doctor sent me up to' Mt. Lowe.
        Q.-Ygu were in bad shape physically at
        that time, as I understand,it?
        A.-Yes, sir.
        Q.-9go ahead.
        A-l went to Mt. Lowe and Mr. Chaplin
        ould not ith e said he had to
        g aw I*= aWd 11d to be away from
        me, for a while. I beWd him to go with
        me, ,but he would not go, so he went to
        Coronado.
        Q.-With whom?
        A.- th 18 secretary, and stayed down
        there a fiew "ye.
        Q-Abo three weeks, you say?
        A.-Ae stayed a few days, and then he
        came back to his house. I could not stand
        it say longer. so I went down to the city
        to ask hib if he would come up with me
        to Mt. Lowe for one day, and he said he
        would not came.
        Q.-Ne said he would not come?
        A.-Tes. So I took quite ill and threat
        mend to do everything In the world If he
        would not come up with me one day, so
        he went up with me for one day and said
        he had to go right down; that he could
        just stay that day.
        Q.-He got up there at what time in the
        morning?
        A.-He went up in the evening and he
        went down the next morning.
        Q.-Then how long before you saw him
        the next time?
        A.-Then he went back to Coronado.
        Q.-Well, how long did he remain there?
        A-He stayed a couple of weeks.
        Q.-Were you Ill all the time you were
        at Mt. Lowe?
        A.-Yes.
        Q.-Who was with you?
        A.-Mother was with me.
        Q.-Now, on this Qhristmas evening you
        have told about, the first Christmas even
        Ing after your marriage In October, you
        had invited your friends there to the
        house, had you?
        A.-No, I had not; Mr. Chaplin bad all
        his own friend.; he did not want me to
        have mine.
        ,Q.-Then, you allege, that he came home
        about what time on Christmas morning?
        A-It was about two-thirty or three.
        Q.-Two-thirty or three. Then nal
        Christmas morning what occurred?
        A-He stayed in bed all day until four
        o'clock; he wouldn't go down stairs with
        me to pee the tree. I took him his
        presents.
        Q.-Did he abuse you?
        A-He was very angry at me for mak
        ing so much over Christmas
        Q.-What did he say?
        A-He said It was very foolish an,1
        wasn't right to make so much or for me
        to like presents and foolish thing.; that
        it was not his idea to have Christmas or
        celebrate Christmas; he had never done It.
        Q.-You allege in your complaint that
        you had always had girl friends of ap
        proximately your own age as companions?
        A-Yes, sir.
        Q.-What condition existed after you
        were parried with reference to whether
        or no~ he would permit your tiends to
        come and visit you?
        A-He did not like them: he didn't
        think that I should see them; he thought
        I should like hi. frend. and be more
        studious.
        Q.-What did he say or do with refer'
        once to your friends V he should find them
        in his house or the house, what was his
        conduct toward them?
        A-He was uot nice to them; he
        wouldn't come home if I bad them.
        Q.-When you had your frends he would
        refuse to come to the house if he found It
        out?
        A.-Ya., air.
        tic Life.
        ich Won Her
        but Not a
        0
        Chpin
        It AU
        -ried him. If was two years. ago
        s. She was seveuseen, he was
        nas.
        ther day, in a Los Angeles court,
        rk listened to Mrs. Chaplin's sworn
        how the great comedlian.played the
        sband-and gave Mrs. Chaplin her
        It was expected that Charlie Chap
        I be a very original and unusual sort
        degrom. He was. Two months
        ey were married Christmas came.
        Drt of frolic would you imaginl
        Chaplin would think up for hig
        a celebration with his young bride?
        we1y, some surprise of course.
        was an entirely unexpected surpried
        s unique way the comedian celebrat
        Christmas is told in Mrs. Chaplin's
        1 as given in the transcript of the
        y at her divorce trial printed be.
        his page.
        sately, Charlie Chaplin himself
        present in court to explain what
        n play the part as his wife described
        judge.
        Q.-Haw oftea did that occur, Mrs.
        Chaplin?
        A.-All the time; he would never tell me
        when he would be home; he said he had to
        be free to live his own life and do as he
        plealed.
        Q.-Now, on that Christmas did he give
        you any present or token of any kind?
        A.-No.
        Q.-Was he earning money in consider
        able amount at that time?
        A.-Yes, sir.
        Q.-He made you no present whatever?
        A.-No, sir.
        Q.-What was your condition at that
        time of your trip to Mt. Lowe?
        A.-I was expecting to be a mother.
        Q.-And he knew that?
        A.-Yes, sir.
        Q.-At that time did you have a contract
        with the Universal Film pompany for your
        services?
        A.-I did.
        Q.-Tell the court about that with refer
        cnce to his insisting on your working when
        you were unable to work?
        A.-Well, when we %rere married Mr.
        Chaplin told me he wanted me to break
        the contract with the Pniversal, because
        he did not want me iorking with them.
        So, when I was in the hbspital, after I was
        first taken ill, I sent a written notice that
        I would not be with them any more and I
        was under age. My lawyer told me we
        could break the contract. Then, in Feb
        ruary. when I came back from Mt. Lowe.
        they had been sendjag me my check each
        -:eek, and I had been sending them back
        and they would return them again, but I
        had not cashed any. In February a friend
        of mine, Miss Bweet, asked me to go to
        New York with her when I came back
        from Mt. Lowe, and Mr. Chaplin had been
        away so long, and when he came back he
        said it would do me good to go to New
        York, so I wentt with her. But he wouldn't
        give me but $150.'and when I got East r
        bought a lot of baby clothes ad some baby
        furniture and a few other things, and I did
        not have enough money and I wired for
        more money. But he would not send me
        any more, so I wired mother to please
        ash one of my checks.
        Q.--That 'was the check that would re
        a-dirm your contract irith the Universal
        -eople, which he advised you to break?
        A-Yes, sir.
        Q.-Did you advise him with reference
        to your circumstances?
        A-Yes.
        Q.-DId you advise him that you expect
        ed to purchase some furniture for the ex
        pected child?
        A-Yes, sir.
        Q.-And he declined to send you any
        money at all?
        A.-Yes.
        Q.-And he was making apozimately
        16,000 or I7,000 a month at that time?
        A.-More than that.
        Q.-You mentioned the furniture. You
        say there was an arrangement made about
        snme turniture for the baby's room?
        A.-BDefore I went East Mr. Chaplin said
        Icould get a set of furniture for my room
        un in our home, because it was very dark.
        Q.-That was the room in which you
        were to be confined?
        A.-Yes, sir; my own roem. So.
        hoght it at Beriker Crothers, end when
        got back from he York the room was all
        =urnished in thE aew furniture, ad he
        took me up to see it, and I was very happy
        about it aid he seemed to be quite pleased.
        but when the bfll came he refused to pay
        it. He said it was too expeasive and tat
        Ishould send it back.
        Q--Did you send It back?
        A.-No, sir.
        Q.-What did you de?
        (Oontinseed on Neat Pugf)
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1921-08-31/ed-1/?sp=3&q=Charlie+Chaplin&st=text&r=-0.08,-0.022,1.16,1.201,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Charlie Chaplin Proclaims
        In the Matrimonial Market Again
        In 3-Minute Hot Weather Interview
        Comedian Strategically Shy on
        Most Questions, but Vents
        Some Positive Opinions
        Doesn't Know What Sort of
        Woman He Likes Best and
        Would .Rather Read Hamlet
        Than Play It.
        By Mar giteriteMooersMar shall
        Charlie Chaplin, tho playboy of the
        movies, Charlie of the funny feet, the
        trained mustache, the Incredible head
        gear, handles ,a three-minute Inter
        view with all the care he does NOT
        bestow on oustard pics and cops.
        Charlie is ever so polite about it, mit
        nevertheless he acts as It he thought
        The Evening World's hot weather
        test In mental speed were a bomb of
        some sort that might go off in his
        hands.
        When I saw the brown-eyed, debo
        nair, soft-voiced little comedian in the
        theatre lobby Just after the rehearsal
        of the next release of his friend Mary
        Pickford and Just before the showing
        of the newest picture of his friend
        Douglas Fairbanks, he leaned against
        the wall for support, wiggled his fin-
        gers nervously and took his full three tatlon. although you'd think him quail
        minutes to nnswer the fifteen qucs- fled to answer this one) Make them
        Hons I had prepared.

        viwot TiTirrTP
        rjiioj juinvj u,
        Gains on Schedule, but Parries Most
        Thrusts.
        It was exactly 17 minutes past 1
        when I asked:
        Q. No. 1 What Is It that makes you
        so funny?
        Charlie Chaplin (grinning bashfully.
        60 that he showed most of his very
        hlto and even teeth, and looking orr
        into space, somewhere over my left
        shoulder) I don't know ask tho kids.
        Q. No. 2 Ought movie salaries to
        go down?
        Charlie Chaplin (straightening his
        drooping shoulders, an Indignant In
        flection In the soft voice) Certainly
        not!
        Q. No 3 Is the Rolshevlk Govern
        ment going to last In Russia?
        Charlie Chaplin I do not know.
        Q. No. 4 Why don't you want to
        marry again?
        Charlie Chaplin (who was recently
        quoted as saying that he didn't, but
        who seoms to have changed his mind
        girls, here's your chance!) Who
        says that I don't? Quoting me to that
        effect was a ralBtafce. I certainly do
        want to marry again very much!
        Q. No. 5 What sort of woman do
        you like best?
        Charlie Chaplin (again grinning em.
        barrasscdly and tying his fingers Into
        bowknots) Now, that's hard to an
        swer; I really couldn't say; I couldn't
        even tell whether she's blond or bru
        nette; I couldn't answer that.
        Q. No. 6 Are you In favor of an
        Irish republic?
        Charlie Chaplin (determinedly play
        ing safe) I prefer to be discreet and
        not commltmyself.
        The first minute was gone and we
        were one answer ahead of the avcrago
        called for by the tlmo schedule.
        SECOND MINUTE.
        Slows Down His Ansuers, but UoUls
        to Schedule.
        Q. No. 7 Should women smoke
        cigarettes?
        Charlie Chaplin (hesitating, Hps
        moving nervously, then smiling dlplo-
        vicw to obtaining an Increase In
        fares. Nathan Kushncr, No. 1057
        Simpson Street, former Interborough
        guard, said that while there was no
        official union statement showing that
        the company was back of the strike.
        It was freely passed from one em
        ployee to another that tho company
        was going bankrupt and that the
        only chance for employees to get a
        pay increase was to help tho company
        obtain a ten-cont fare which tho
        company would share.
        Commissioner Hirsuficld said that
        the Interborough receivership move
        In designed to got an Increased fare.
        Tho Transit Commission, ho said,
        fears to gTant an Incrcaso for political
        reasons. If tho company gots a
        "friendly receiver, ns in tho cose of
        the D. It. T.," ho predicted, "It will
        separate its elevated and subway
        systoms, doing away wlln transfers,
        and thus getting the equivalent of a
        I fare increase,"
        MAKEi VOU FUNHV
        SHOULD
        i AUAt?l C.S GO DOWN r"
        i-v-"rwe. QqusHcvik govt.
        WHV DONT YOU 'wAKl-r
        WOMH bQVQU
        LI KB. OE5T
        DO YOITC.VOR.
        WOMEN SfrvlOKC
        oovoo itsm-icvi;
        wm,t qovoo
        DOWITW YOUR
        MOM JCV
        OOV T HEtPTHC
        ON EMPI.OVCD?
        wi-wr isthc
        EVSICtTr WAV
        "TO MAKE PEODLE
        IAU&H it'YOO
        JVCRENOT, A. MCVIC
        SfAtfc WHAT WOULD
        Vvuix-r i w-.. r:
        THE VOISTKAOIAW,
        PIES HAVf
        VOU WUINtD IN -YOOCL
        CAREER -p
        matloully) That depends
        woman!
        Q. No. 8 Do you believe In national
        censorship of the movies? m
        Charlie Chaplin (repeating the
        question to gain tlmo and thinking
        hard) Do I believe In national cen
        sorship? Yesif It's intelligent.
        Q. No. 9 Whit do you do with all
        your money?
        Charlie Chaplin (tho hundred candle-power
        grin again turned on) Pay
        my taxes and spend some now and
        then.
        Q. No. 10 What should the Govern
        ment do to help the unemployed?
        Charlie Chaplin (who takes a de
        cidedly sorious, non-facellous Interest
        in labor and social problems) They
        should do a great dcal-so much that
        I couldn't begin to cover the subject
        een if I todk the whole time you
        allow for tho Interview.
        Tho second minute was up, and we
        had lost our one-answer lead owing
        to the comedian's habit of stopping to
        think before he spoke.

        Finishes Exactly on Time and Seems
        Glad It's Ocer.
        Q. No. 11 What is the easiest way
        to make people laugh?
        Charlie Chaplin (with modest hesl-
        nappy. I guess uui someutxiy eiso
        could answer that question a good
        de-'11 better than 1.
        Q. No. 12 If you weie not a movie
        star, what would you like to be?
        Charlie Chaplin (with a quiet
        chuckle) Night watchman.
        Q. No. 13 Hqw many custard pies
        have you ruined since tho beginning
        of your career a million?
        Charlie Chaplin Oh, not as many
        as that. Say a. thousand!
        Q. No. 14 What is your
        opinion of the Volstead act?
        Charlie Chaplin (the laugh
        candid
        In
        ins
        eyes, as well as on his lips, and look
        ing me straight In the face for almost
        the first time during the Interview)
        Of the Volstead act? You must ex
        cuse me I don't use such language!
        Q. No. 15 When ate you going to
        play Hamlet?
        Charlie Chaplin 'although this role
        is said to bo his dearest ambition)
        I'd rather read It. What I really want
        in my future work is to do as I please
        to follow my own whim!
        The interview and the three minutes
        were over. Charlie seemed glad the
        bomb had not exploded!
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024827/1921-10-02/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Charlie+Chaplin&st=text&r=-0.177,-0.068,1.353,1.353,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        CHARLIE CHAPLIN WRITES HIS IMPRESSIONS OF AMERICA
        LONDON, Oct. 1. I always figure
        America under the symbol of youth
        vigorous, aggressive, full of hope and
        pen. courageous, and with the sun
        light of the morning shining in its
        eyes.
        I find England more like a serene
        old age mellowed by time, softened
        ly suffering, wise from long experi
        ence and with the. afterglow of the
        westering sun in its eyes.
        America, like all youth, has a core
        of hardness in its heart.
        England, like all mellowed old age
        has a core of tenderness in its heart.
        I should say America for work,
        England for thoughtful contempla
        tion and dreams.
        Of course, I know England is one of
        the mightiest nations in the world;
        that its hardy sons rule an empire;
        that they sail all seas and traffic In
        all markets. But I am merely trying
        to give my own impressions, to tell
        how the two countries 'affect me.
        I don't think I could do much work
        in England. Everything Is so finish
        ed, so settled, so restful that it would
        simply absorb' me.
        America Is Restless
        nut there Is in America a feeling of
        the unfinished, of restlessness that
        ius. makes one want to get up and do
        thjngs. That is why I am going back
        In a few weeks.
        It's all very nice to say that Chap
        lin brings laughter to men, but the
        truth is that Chaplin is working for
        his bread and cheese just like the
        rest of you. There is not much fun
        jn loafing too long.
        I have been rediscovering England
        for myself aiyl contrasting my Im
        pressions of America and also with
        my memeories of the England I knew
        as a boy.
        I came to America when I was 18
        und In the past 14 years have only
        been back home once.
        My best experience has been to ram
        ble around the streets in the poor
        sections of London that I 'used
        know. I found in the mean streets
        something very lovely, something spir
        itunl. I nian as regards the people.
        There they were, living in misera
        ble tenements, their faces thin and
        pinehed from poor food, and yet there
        w something very beautiful in their
        eye.
        I. have never seen anything sweeter
        than the expression in the face of a
        girl out walking with her coster Tcrer.
        I began to understand how these
        poor people had suffered during the
        long years of the war and how thev
        had found the pluck to do it. and 1
        saw the mak rit had left on them. It
        was saddening as well as beautiful to
        get these -revelations.
        Had "Emotional Jag"
        Then I had an emotional jag. I
        prowled these poor streets in search
        or a wistful little bov I used to know
        a little, ill-dressed, rather fright
        ened Charlie Chaplin.
        Somehow. I couldn't quite catch up
        with him. The streets all seemed nar
        rower to me than they did to that
        little chap, and the crowds not quite
        so big and bustling, and the policemen
        not quite so terrifying.
        1
        N
        I
        it I
        -3- Vy
        i
        "ft:
        4 V;
        CHARLIE CHAPLIN
        But I did see something we haven't
        got in America. eaw the mark Iof
        class distinction. The population In
        England Is really subdivided into real
        classes and castes. And being a very
        I old civilization and a very crowded
        country, it is hard for a man to get
        ou of his class.
        We have none of that in America.
        The workman of today still has the
        chance to be the captain of, industry
        of tomorrow. Why, the poor editor of
        yesterday is the president of today!
        America" is still in thd construction
        stage. She is not finished. That i
        why the builders, who are at work on
        the structure today, should be so very
        careful.
        It seems to me, looking back
        across the waters and across time,
        that America Is in a very critical pe
        riod. 1
        Finance is once, more in danger of
        falling into the 1 bands of the few we
        always call "Wall Street."
        And finance is adapting a taa Intol
        erant attitude toward labor. Labor
        should not be -asked to do all the giv
        ing un. Finance should give up a lit
        tle, also."
        There is a danger that if there is
        too much clash, a class feeling will
        develon which would be entirely un
        American. Too Much Organization
        I think "another danger to America
        is the number 'of organizations which
        are growing up which are anti-some-bodyq,
        anti-some religion or race or
        creed or free expression of thought.
        America can learn a lesson in this
        regard from old England. There is
        far greater personal liberty and far
        greater iibertv of speech in England
        than in America.
        Since havle been over here I have
        seen it stated that I am a deep reader
        and that I am a Socialist. I would
        like to deny both statements. I am
        not a highbrow. I don't pretend to
        be. My only pretension is to be an
        rtist. I don't mix in, politics. And
        I am nol immersed in economic litera
        tu. i
        I am neither, a Socialist 'nor a par
        lor Bolshevik. But I believe with all
        mv heart in social reform. I believe
        very strongly in municipal ownership
        of public utilities. I believe in the
        nationalization of the railways and
        probably of coai mines.
        In 20 years one. million,. eight hun
        dred and eighty-three thousand homes
        have been broken up in the United
        States by divorce courts.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86063496/1919-03-14/ed-1/seq-13/#date1=1756&index=0&rows=20&words=CHAPLIN+CHARLIE&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Charlie+Chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        - MR. and MRS.
        CHARLIE
        CHAPLIN
        BTheatre Bway at 4/â€™ St.
        Â¢ DirÃ©ction: M. KASHIN
        ANTRCEEIE
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn81004351/1936-03-22/ed-1/seq-17/#date1=1756&index=2&rows=20&words=CHAPLIN+Chaplin+CHARLIE+Charlie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Charlie+Chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        DIRECTOR; Ignacio E. Lozano
        CHARLIE CHAPLIN, por Rodney de Sarro.
        Tras un retiro de varios años, Charlie Chaplin, el inimitable artista de la pantalla, vuelve a deleitarnos en su última película
        titulada TIEMPOS MODERNOS, en la cual trabaja con Paulette Goddard. El famoso caricaturista Rodney de Sarro, presen
        ta aquí su impresión de Chaplin, en esta acuarela especial y exclusiva para nuestros lectores. (United Artists.)
        LA OPINION
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1921-07-17/ed-1/seq-51/#date1=1756&index=7&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charlie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Charlie+Chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Jackie Coogan. who appeared tirst with Charlie Chaplin as 1^.. B
        Had Roy,'' a WH^H^^^^HR|H
        mother not be H
        a t IHp HRHuK
        *?k. (W^^9^j|^^K^| I ^Hjjj
        ?^g^fe-:|^g^^Hft., ^Pr ||fi.
        .??? ,
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1921-02-13/ed-1/seq-24/#date1=1756&index=9&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charlie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Charlie+Chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        "The Kid," of which Charlie Chaplin is the author,
        actor, and producer, gives its agile creator great opportunity
        for the display of his gymnastic gifts. The kid,
        played by Jack Coogan, is little less agile than his in-'
        imitable parent.. Mustard plaster, having more of a
        tang to it, supplants custard pie as a missile. The kid
        can throw stones with precision and elude capture by
        a cop with great dexterity.
        Charlie's dream of a heavenly state where the police
        wear wings, is quite a new conception, and is lovely,
        until the feathers of the angel wings, fly in a free for
        all scrap. . *
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn81004351/1928-01-15/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1756&index=6&rows=20&words=Chaplin+Charlie&searchType=basic&sequence=0&state=&date2=1963&proxtext=Charlie+Chaplin&y=0&x=0&dateFilterType=yearRange&page=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        ¿Reconoce usted, lector, a la guapa Mae Murray, al terrible
        Premier Mussoiini, al intrépido Lindbergh. al hombre de acero Hin
        denburg, al dolorido Charlie Chaplin y al peligroso monstruo que
        va por todas las calles amenazando nuestra vida?
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>/</id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
